{
  "title": "Computer_Network - Network_Security — Slot 1 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Network_Security — Slot 1",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Avalanche effect in cryptography refers <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Large changes in cipher text when the keyword is changed minimally</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Large changes in cipher text when the plain text is changed</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Large Impact of keyword change to length of the cipher text</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Large changes in cipher text when the keyword is changed minimally</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331416/isro2020-45\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>In a columnar transportation cipher, the plain text is \"the tomato is a plant in the night shade family\", keyword is \"TOMATO\". The cipher text is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\"TINESAX / EOAHTFX / HTLTHEY / MAIIAIX / TAPNGDL / OSTNHMX\"</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\"TINESAX / EOAHTFX / MAIIAIX / HTLTHEY / TAPNGDL / OSTNHMX\"</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\"TINESAX / EOAHTFX / HTLTHEY / MAIIAIX / OSTNHMX / TAPNGDL\"</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\"EOAHTFX / TINESAX / HTLTHEY / MAIIAIX / TAPNGDL / OSTNHMX\"</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\"TINESAX / EOAHTFX / HTLTHEY / MAIIAIX / TAPNGDL / OSTNHMX\"</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331415/isro2020-44\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>In an RSA cryptosystem, the value of the public modulus parameter n is 3007. If it is also is known that \\(\\phi(n)=2880\\), where \\(\\phi()\\) denotes Euler's Totient Function, then the prime factors of n which is greater than 50 is _________ . <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2019)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "97",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/302794/gate2019-cs-54#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following algorithm is not used in asymmetric key cryptography? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2018)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>RSA Algorithm</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Gillie-Hellman Algorithm</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Electronic Code Book Algorithm</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Electronic Code Book Algorithm</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/213510/isro2018-78\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>What is one advantage of setting up a DMZ (Demilitarized Zone) with two firewalls? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2018)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>You can control where traffic goes in the three networks</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>You can do statefull packet filtering</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>You can do load balancing</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Improve network performance</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>You can control where traffic goes in the three networks</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/213511/isro2018-77\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Avalanche effect in cryptography <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2018)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Is desirable property of cryptographic algorithm</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Is undesirable property of cryptographic algorithm</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Has no effect on encryption algorithm</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Is desirable property of cryptographic algorithm</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/213514/isro2018-74\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>In cryptography, the following uses transposition ciphers and the keyword is LAYER. Encrypt the following message. (Spaces are omitted during encrypton)<br>WELCOME TO NETWORK SECURITY! <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2018)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>WMEKREETSILTWETCOOCYONRU!</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>EETSICOOCYWMEKRONRU!LTWET</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>LTWETONRU!WMEKRCOOCYEETSI</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>ONRU!COOCYLTWETEETSIWMEKR</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>EETSICOOCYWMEKRONRU!LTWET</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/213542/isro2018-46\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Pretty Good Privacy (PGP) is used in: <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Browser security</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>FTP security</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Email security</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Email security</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128669/isro2017-37\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>MD5 is a widely used hash function for producing hash value of <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>64 bits</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>128 bits</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>512 bits</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1024 bits</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>128 bits</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128663/isro2017-35\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>In a RSA cryptosystem a participant A uses two prime numbers p=13 and q=17 to generate\nher public and private keys. If the public key of A is 35. Then the private key of A is\n__________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "11",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118327/gate2017-1-44#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>A sender S sends a message m to receiver R, which is digitally signed by S with its\nprivate key. In this scenario, one or more of the following security violations can take place. <br><br>\nI. S can launch a birthday attack to replace m with a fraudulent message.<br>\nII. A third party attacker can launch a birthday attack to replace m with a fraudulent message  <br>  III. R can launch a birthday attack to replace m with a fraudulent message.<br><br>\nWhich of the following are possible security violations? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I and II only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>II only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II and III only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>I only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118295/gate2017-1-15#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>If a class C is derived from class B, which is derived form class A, all through public inheritance, then a class C member function can access <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>only protected and public data of C and B</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only protected and public data of C</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>all data of C and private data of A and B</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>public and protected data of A and B and all data of C</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>public and protected data of A and B and all data of C</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55530/isro2016-78\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Anarkali digitally signs a message and sends it to Salim. Verification of the signature by Salim requires <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Anarkali's public key</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Salim's public key.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Salim's private key</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Anarkali's private key</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Anarkali's public key</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39555/gate2016-2-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Consider that B wants to send a message m that is digitally signed to A. Let the pair of private and public keys for A and B be denoted by \\(K_{x}^{-}\\)\nand \\(K_{x}^{+}\\) for x = A,B, respectively. Let  \\(K_{x}(m)\\)\nrepresent the operation of encrypting m with a key \\(K_{x}\\) and H(m) represent the message digest. Which one of the following indicates the CORRECT way of sending the message m along with the digital signature to A? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>{\\(m,K^{+}_{B}(H(m))\\)}</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{-}_{B}(H(m))}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{-}_{A}(H(m))}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{+}_{A}(H(m))}\\)}</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>{\\({m,K^{-}_{B}(H(m))}\\)}</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39694/gate2016-1-52#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that everyone in a group of N people wants to communicate secretly with the N-1 others using symmetric key cryptographic system. The communication between any two persons should not be decodable by the others in the group. The number of keys required in the system as a whole to satisfy the confidentiality requirement is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2N</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>N(N-1)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>N(N-1)/2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\((N-1)^{2}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>N(N-1)/2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8244/gate2015-1-14#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}